

VENKATESH KESARBANDI

AWS Solutions Architect

PROFILE

AWS 2x Certified, 15years of rich experienced specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Data Analysis, Cloud Computing, Amazon Web Services, ITIL, Backup, and DR Solutions. Strong professional with a Bachelor of Engineering focused in Computer Science from M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology. Chess Player, YouTuber, and an Udemy Instructor

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91 9886 956 642

EMAIL:

venkatesh111@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/venkatesh111/

Udemy Course

www.udemy.com/course/awscloudmigration/

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solution Architect Associate
- AWS Developer Associate
- ITIL V3 Certified



EDUCATION

M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology - Bangalore

Year: 2002 - 2006

Degree: Bachelor of Engineering Specialization: Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM India Private Limited - **Infrastructure Specialist** Dec 2016 - Till date

- Strong Operational skills on Cloud Services EC2, S3, VPC, IAM, Load Balancers, Auto scaling, Lambda, API Gateway, Storage Gateway, Cloud watch, Cloud trail.
- Building Infrastructure as Code using CloudFormation
- Application Deployments on ECS, Elastic Beanstalk
- Completing Onboarding Activities via Ansible for new projects, Cloud Native Automation using AWS Systems Manager
- Follow Agile Methodologies for Project management
- Weekly Calls with customer to understand new requirement and share teams work for the week.
- Conduct Technical trainings for the team, Cross train engineers from different technology about Cloud and AWS and helping them with their carrier guidance

Hewlett Packard - Delivery Lead

Jan 2009 - Nov 2016

- Handle Transition Activities
- Conduct Technical Interviews to hire new employees
- Interact with Customer on bi-weekly calls and provide updates on team activities, take inputs and feedback from customer
- DR activities with stipulated RTO/RPO
- Train new Joiners and prepare them for Production related activities

Unisys Global Services India - Systems Engineer Sept 2006 – Jan 2009

 Provide all levels of support with regard to System Administration and NetBackup related Issues

SKILLS

